<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

   <statements version="1.0" htmlParse="false">
     <statement id="1">Voting is an essential responsibility of every Canadian citizen.</statement>
     <statement id="2">My vote has a meaningful impact on election outcomes.</statement>
     <statement id="3">I feel personally motivated to vote in elections.</statement>
     <statement id="4">People who don’t vote are failing in their civic duties.</statement>
     <statement id="5">I have faced challenges when trying to vote in Canada.</statement>
     <statement id="6">The voting process in Canada is accessible to all citizens.</statement>
     <statement id="7">Online voting would significantly increase voter participation.</statement>
     <statement id="8">Work, childcare, or other logistical issues make it hard for me to vote.</statement>
     <statement id="9">I trust that Canada’s electoral system is fair and transparent.</statement>
     <statement id="10">Politicians represent the interests of ordinary Canadians.</statement>
     <statement id="11">My level of trust in the government directly affects my decision to vote.</statement>
     <statement id="12">Corruption or dishonesty in politics discourages me from voting.</statement>
     <statement id="13">I feel well-informed about candidates and political parties during elections.</statement>
     <statement id="14">Canadians need better education on the importance of voting.</statement>
     <statement id="15">I actively seek information about election issues before voting.</statement>
     <statement id="16">A lack of information about candidates or parties discourages me from voting.</statement>
     <statement id="17">My family and social circle encourage me to vote.</statement>
     <statement id="18">There is a stigma in Canada around not voting.</statement>
     <statement id="19">Cultural or linguistic barriers make it harder for some communities to vote.</statement>
     <statement id="20">Young Canadians are less likely to vote because they feel disconnected from politics.</statement>
   </statements>